{
    "id": "2a95407fcbed410da7b20096443a90aa",
    "title": "Conjunctions And Prepositions Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "I will not come …………………… he invites me.",
            "description": "Except is not equivalent to unless. Unless means if not.",
            "answers": [
                "unless",
                "if",
                "except"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "Put everything …………………… the vase in the box.",
            "description": "Except is a preposition. It means excluding or other than.",
            "answers": [
                "except",
                "without",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "I will not go ……………………….. you do.",
            "description": "Unless is not equivalent to without.",
            "answers": [
                "without",
                "unless",
                "except"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "He walks ……………………….. his father does.",
            "description": "Like is a preposition as is a conjunction. We need a conjunction to connect two clauses.",
            "answers": [
                "as",
                "like",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "……………………….. he had gone, cops knocked at the door.",
            "description": "As soon as is used to connect two actions that happen in quick succession.",
            "answers": [
                "No sooner",
                "Hardly",
                "As soon as"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "……………………….. had he gone, when someone knocked at the door.",
            "description": "We use an inverted word order after hardly and scarcely.",
            "answers": [
                "Scarcely",
                "Hardly",
                "As soon as",
                ""
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "No sooner had he returned from the city ………………………… he started feeling ill.",
            "description": "No sooner is followed by than.",
            "answers": [
                "than",
                "when",
                "before"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "He was buried in the village …………………………… he was born.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "there",
                "where",
                "which"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "He washed ………………………… his hands nor his face.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "neither",
                "either",
                "nor"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "I waited ……………………….. he arrived.",
            "description": "Till is used of time.",
            "answers": [
                "till",
                "upto",
                "as far as"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "I have eaten nothing ………………………… I left home.",
            "description": "Since can refer to time. It indicates the starting point of something. ",
            "answers": [
                "from",
                "since",
                "as"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I went ................................. him.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "except",
                "without",
                "unless"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        }
    ]
}